getguru.com 2019-08-14

# Our Privacy Policy at Guru | Guru

Last Modified: June, 13th, 2018

Thank you for using Guru. At Guru, we know that you care how your information is treated, so we’ve created this Privacy Policy (sometimes referred to as the “Policy”), which focuses on how we collect personally identifiable (or “personal”) information. Personal information identifies or describes a particular individual, such as a person’s first and last name, email address, physical address or telephone number.

This Policy applies to our websites, services, products, and applications (each a “Service”) and explains the following:

  * What information we gather from you when you use the Service
  * How we may use and share this information
  * The security approaches we use to protect your information

We will not use or share your personal information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy.

By using the Service, you consent to the collection and use of your personal information by Guru in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will post those changes on this page and revise the “last modified” date on the Policy. Your access to and use of this Service is also subject to your acceptance of [Guru’s Terms of Service](https://www.getguru.com/terms-of-service/).

### Information We Collect and Use

We collect only the minimum personal information necessary to operate, maintain and provide you the features and functionality of the Service, to analyze how the Service is used, diagnose service or technical problems, maintain security, personalize content, remember information to help you efficiently access your account, monitor aggregate metrics such as total number of visitors, traffic, and demographic patterns, and track Content and users as necessary to comply with the Digital Millennium Copyright Act (“DMCA”) and other applicable laws. “Content” refers to information, messages, text and other data which is collected, stored, surfaced, and shared through the use of our Service.

 **Information You Provide:** You provide us information about yourself, such as your name and e-mail address, if you register for an account with the Service or by connecting with the Service via a third-party service, which includes “following,” “favoriting,” “becoming a fan,” adding the Guru application, etc., on a third party website or network. We receive and store the information you input when registering for our Service, or which you otherwise provide to us in any other manner.

We may use your email address to send you Service-related notices (including any notices required by law, in lieu of communication by postal mail). We may also use your contact information to send you marketing messages. If you do not want to receive these messages, you can opt out by following the instructions in the message.

If you choose to use our invitation service to invite a friend to the Service, we will ask you for that person’s email address and automatically send an email invitation. We store this information to send this email, to register your friend if your invitation is accepted, and to track the success of our invitation service.

 **Content:** You also provide us Content you post to the Service, or is otherwise collected through your use of the Service. Your Content and metadata about your Content may be viewed by other users in accordance with your settings on the Service. Unless Content is made viewable in accordance with your settings on the Service, then neither Guru, Guru employees, Guru contractors nor agents will view your Content except: (i) to maintain, provide or improve the Service; (ii) to help you and respond to your request related to your Content, including support requests; (iii) to review and monitor (if we elect to do so) compliance with our Terms of Service (including our Acceptable Use Policy); (iv) to comply with or avoid the violation of applicable law or regulation (including to review and remove allegedly infringing Content in accordance with the DMCA), or to cooperate with law enforcement; or (v) as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. We have the right to remove any information you post, if deemed to be in violation of our Acceptable Use Policy as set forth in our [Terms of Service](http://www.getguru.com/terms-of-service/).

 **Cookies;** When you use the Service, we may send one or more “cookies” – a small data file – to your computer to uniquely identify your browser and let us help you log in faster and enhance your navigation through the Guru site. A cookie may convey anonymous information about how you browse the Service to us. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive after you close your browser so that it can be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the Service. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your web browser’s directions. A session cookie is temporary and disappears after you close your browser. You can reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent; however, some features of the Service may not function properly if the ability to accept cookies is disabled.

Note that certain third parties engaged by your employer or e-mail provider (or your e-mail provider itself) may use cookies. The use of such third party cookies is not covered by this Policy, as we do not have access or control over these cookies. Please check with the relevant third parties’ privacy policies to understand how they may use cookies.

 **Log Files:** When you use the Service, our servers automatically record certain information sent by your web browser. These server logs may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, referring / exit pages and URLs, number of clicks and how you interact with links on the Service, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, mobile carrier, and other such information.

 **Clear Gifs Information:** When you use the Service, we may employ clear gifs (also known as web beacons) which are used to track the online usage patterns. In addition, we may also use clear gifs in HTML-based emails we send to our users to track which emails are opened by recipients. The information is used to enable more accurate reporting and make our Service better.

 **Third Party Tools:** We use third party tools for ad targeting/tailoring, remarketing, conversion tracking, user assessment and analytics tools, such as, yet not limited to Twitter, Google AdWords, Intercom, Wootric, and Google Analytics, to help understand use of the Service. Many of these tools collect the information as sent by your browser as part of a web page request, including cookies and your IP address. These tools also receive this information and their use of it is governed by their privacy policy and opt out provisions, where applicable.

 **Do Not Track:** If you enable or send a “do not track” signal or similar mechanism relating to the tracking of browsing activities, we do not have practices or protocols to honor or respond to such a request. However, we only collect the types of information otherwise described in this Policy.

### How We Share Your Information

 **Your Use:** We will display certain personal information about you in your profile page and elsewhere on the Service according to the preferences you set in your e-mail account(s). Any information you choose to provide should reflect how much you want others to know about you. Please consider carefully what information you disclose in your profile page and your desired level of anonymity. You can review and revise your profile information at any time. We may also share or disclose your personal information with your consent, and also as otherwise described below.

 **Service Providers, Business Partners, and Others:** We may share your personal information with other third parties (such as trusted contractors or service providers who host our Service or otherwise support the operation of the Service). If we do this, such third parties’ use of your information will be bound terms which are substantially similar to this Privacy Policy as applicable to the services which they are providing for us. We may also store personal information in locations outside our direct control (for instance, on servers or databases co-located with hosting providers).

If we receive personal data subject to our certification under the Privacy Shield and then transfer it to a third-party service provider acting as an agent on our behalf, we have certain liability under the Privacy Shield if both (i) the agent processes the personal data in a manner inconsistent with the Privacy Shield and (ii) we are responsible for the event giving rise to the misuse.

 **Business Transfers:** As we develop our business, we may buy or sell assets or business offerings. Customers, email, and visitor information is generally one of the transferred business assets in these types of transactions and we may transfer your personal information in these instances. We may also transfer or assign such information in the course of corporate divestitures, mergers, or dissolution. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to notify you of any change of ownership or control in which your personal information is transferred.

 **Third Party Services:** You may share your information with a third party application either with your consent or in a situation where you give a third party access to your Content, information and/or account (for example when you choose to access our Services through such an application). We are not responsible for what those parties do with your information, so you should make sure you trust the application and that it has a privacy policy acceptable to you.

 **Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement Requests; Protection of Guru’s Rights:** We may disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or subpoena or if we believe that it is reasonably necessary to comply with a law, regulation or legal request; to protect the safety of any person; to address fraud, security or technical issues; or to protect our rights or property.

 **Non­Personally Identifiable Information:** We may disclose your non-private, aggregated, anonymized or otherwise non-personally identifiable information, such as anonymous usage data, platform types, etc., with interested third parties to help them understand the usage patterns for certain Guru Services.

### How We Protect Your Information

The security of your information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) as part of our Service, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure sockets layer technology (SSL).

We’ve also adopted commercially reasonable physical, managerial, and technical safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of your personal information. For example, we regularly back up your data to help prevent data loss and aid in data recovery. We also guard against common web attack vectors, host data in secure SOC 1, SOC 2, ISO 27001 and ISO 9001 compliant data center facilities, and implement industry standard firewalls and access restrictions on our servers to secure our network. No method of electronic transmission or storage is 100% secure, however, and we cannot ensure or warrant the absolute security of any information you transmit or store in the Service.

In the event that personal information is compromised as a result of a security breach, we will promptly notify the affected parties in accordance with our notification procedures set forth in this Privacy Policy, or as otherwise required by applicable law.

### Your Choices About Your Information

You may, of course, decline to submit personal information through the Service, in which case we may not be able to provide certain services to you. You may update or correct your account information at any time by logging in to your account. If you have any other requests or questions related to our handling, use or sharing of your personal information, please contact us at [privacy@getguru.com](mailto:privacy@getguru.com).

### Guru Blog & Community

Our Service offers publicly accessible community services including blogs, and forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. Your posts may remain even after you cancel your account.

### Children’s Privacy

Our Service is not directed to persons under 13, and we do not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register with the Service. If we become aware that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information. If you believe that we may have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at [privacy@getguru.com](mailto:privacy@getguru.com)

### EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

We comply with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, as well as the GPDR, we will process data subject requests (as directed by the customer or “data controller”) and resolve complaints about our collection or use of personal information. EU and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints relative to our data collection should contact: [privacy@getguru.com](mailto:privacy@getguru.com).

All other complaints shall be resolved through alternative dispute resolution. We have selected the International Centre for Dispute Resolution, the international division of the American Arbitration Association ("ICDR/AAA"), as our administrator for non-HR disputes. You may find more information about dispute resolution and how to file a claim with the ICDR/AAA at <http://go.adr.org/privacyshield.html>.

Individuals have the possibility, under certain conditions, to invoke binding arbitration for complaints regarding Privacy Shield compliance not resolved by any of the other Privacy Shield mechanisms. Please visit Annex I for additional information: <https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction>.

We also commit to cooperate with competent EU data protection authorities (DPAs) with regard to our customers end users’ human resources data transferred from a European country participating in the Privacy Shield in the context of the employment relationship.

### Trade Commission Enforcement

Our Privacy Shield compliance is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission (FTC).

### Links to Other Web Sites

We are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from the Service, nor the information or content contained therein. Please remember that when you use a link to go from the Service to another website, our Privacy Policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any other website, including those that have a link on our website, is subject to that website’s own rules and policies.

### Changes to Our Privacy Policy

If we change our Privacy Policy, we will post those changes on this page to keep you aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may disclose it. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

### Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [privacy@getguru.com](mailto:privacy@getguru.com).
